One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
It's all right! It's time to move on
‫لا بأس! هيا نمضي قُدمًا‬
The sun shines always in our hearts
‫فالشمس تُدفئ قلوبنا دومًا‬
Hand in hand, we convey our power
‫قوةٌ تعبر بين أيادينا المتشابكة‬
And make our wishes come true
‫هيا نُحقق أمنياتنا‬
Combining our strengths, we'll crest these surging seas
‫لنركب الأمواج العاتية بالعمل معًا‬
Hurry toward the thrill of danger— Let the adventure begin!
‫لنسرع إلى التشويق... ها هي إشارة البداية‬
Now's the time to set sail; raise the anchor
‫قد حان وقتُ الإبحار، فلنرفع المرساة‬
Off to the seas of adventure, through rainbow-colored winds
‫عبر الريح الملونة بألوان الطيف نخترق صوبَ بحرِ المغامرة‬
Our journey's fraught with injury
‫لن تسلم رحلتنا من الإصابات‬
But what we cherish most is right at our side
‫لكن ما نعتز به سيكون هناك‬
And if you get into a jam
‫وإن وقعت في مأزق‬
I'll always be there to protect you
‫ستجدني معك لأحميك‬
It's all right! It's time to move on
‫لا بأس هيا نمضي قُدمًا‬
The sun shines always in our hearts
‫فالشمس تُدفئ قلوبنا دومًا‬
Shoulder to shoulder, we face all coming storms
‫حتى إن عصفت عاصفة سنعانق بعضنا‬
And look to the future for the light of hope
‫ونوجه ناظرنا نحو الضوء البعيد‬
If we gather up the pieces of our dreams
‫إن جمعنا شظايا أحلامنا‬
They'll make a chart leading to tomorrow
‫سنُشكل خريطةً تقودنا إلى الغد‬
We come together under the same Jolly Roger
‫لذا لنُحقق أمنياتنا‬
And make our wishes come true; together, we are...
‫علمٌ واحد يجمعنا، نحن واحد‬
The Day of the Verdict
‫في يوم المحاكمة‬
Hey Franky, hold up!
‫مهلاً، انتظر يا فرانكي‬
Huh? What–
‫ما الّذي...‬
Put on some pants before you go!
‫ارتدِ بعض السّراويل على الأقلّ‬
Seriously, didn't you learn your lesson the first time?
‫يا إلهي... ألم تتعلّم درسك في المرّة الأولى؟‬
Just wearing your swimsuit will cause another perv alert, you know?
‫إن ذهبت للبلدة بملابس السّباحة فقط‬ ‫سيتّهمونك بالانحراف ثانيةً، صحيح؟‬
Whatever. I'm just getting a few supplies.
‫تبًّا... سأذهب للتّسوّق فحسب‬
Mr. Tom
‫توم-سان‬
Go on. Get moving, then.
‫هيّا، اذهب الآن‬
What a joke preparing this big meal just to celebrate Mr. Tom's acquittal...
‫يا إلهي... لا أصدّق أنّها تكلّف‬ ‫نفسها عناء إعداد‬
I mean, Mr. Tom was innocent from the get-go.
‫لم يكن مذنبًا من الأساس‬
Now, then...
‫والآن...‬
Hey, Mr. Tom and Iceburg! Rise and shine!
‫يا توم-سان، أيسبرغ، انهضا‬
Today's the big trial!
‫اليوم هو يوم المحاكمة‬
Go and get judged already!
‫أسرع واذهب لتلقّي حكمك‬
Hurry to the wharf!
‫أسرعوا إلى الميناء‬
They're handing down Tom's verdict!
‫سيصدرون حكمًا في حقّ توم‬
Quite the turnout for the trial.
‫يبدو أنّ النّاس مهتمّون جدًّا بهذه المحاكمة‬
Court spectators are coming aboard in droves.
‫أخذ الكثير من حضور المحكمة يصعدون للسّفينة‬
Did you see the sea train, Your Honor?
‫هل رأيت القطار البحريّ أيّها القاضي؟‬
Indeed. I rode it once.
‫نعم، ركبتُ على متنه مرّةً‬
It's marvelous. A truly impressive accomplishment.
‫إنّه مذهل بحقّ، أنا منبهر لأنّه صنعه بالفعل‬
Now that the four islands are connected,
‫بعد الرّبط بين الجزر الأربع‬
I doubt anyone would object to his acquittal.
‫أعتقد أنّ لا أحد سيعارض تبرئته‬
Is Tom here yet?
‫هل أتى توم؟‬
I can't wait for it to start.
‫لا أطيق الانتظار لبداية المحاكمة‬
Hurry, before the spectators' gallery fills up!
‫أسرع، سيمتلئ رواق الحضور‬
You said it! I wanna see him walk free with my own eyes!
‫أجل، عليّ أن أشهد على لحظة تبرئته بأمّ عينيّ‬
Man, I can't believe it's been fourteen years already.
‫هذا يعيد الذّكريات إلى الأذهان‬ ‫مرّت 14 سنة بالفعل، صحيح؟‬
What?! Explosions?!
‫ما هذه الانفجارات؟‬
Get off the ship! Everyone, hurry!
‫ترجّلوا من السّفينة‬
Is this some sort of pirate raid?!
‫ما الّذي يجري؟ غارة قراصنة؟‬
Dammit! Where are these shells coming from?
‫سحقًا، من أين يطلقون؟‬
Huh...? Over there!
‫هناك‬
Whose fleet is that?!
‫ما ذلك الأسطول؟‬
I've never seen battleships like that! Which pirate group is it?!
‫لم أرَ سفنًا حربيّة مثلها، أيّ جماعة قراصنة هم؟‬
What the hell are those?! They're covered in guns!
‫ما قصّة تلك السّفن المدجّجة بالأسلحة؟‬
Get away from the wharf! Quickly, now! Run!
‫ابتعدوا عن الميناء‬
Hurry!
‫بسرعة‬
Head into town at once!
‫اهربوا إلى البلدة‬
Help! My son's getting trampled!
‫النّجدة، ابني عالق‬
Why...?
‫لماذا...؟‬
Who is that?!
‫من الّذي... أخذ... سفني؟‬
Mr. Tom, there's trouble!
‫توم-سان، ثمّة مشكلة‬
Franky's ships are firing on the judicial ship!
‫سفن فرانكي تهاجم السّفينة القضائيّة‬
Calm down. It can't be Franky. He just left for town.
‫مهلاً، ليس فرانكي فهو في البلدة الآن‬
I know that! Even he wouldn't do something like this.
‫يستحيل أن يفعل شيئًا كذلك،‬ ‫أنا واثق من هذا‬
That's exactly why this is trouble!
‫ولهذا نحن في مشكلة‬
Let's stop them, Iceburg!
‫سنوقفها يا أيسبرغ‬
Okay!
‫أجل‬
Pirates...? Or maybe the government...?
‫أهم قراصنة؟ أو أحد من الحكومة؟‬
Evacuate!
‫أخلوا المكان‬
Don't stop! Move farther inland!
‫لا تتوقّفوا، أسرعوا إلى البلدة‬
Get away from the docks!
‫ابتعدوا عن الميناء‬
My father's still on the ship!
‫ما زال أبي في الدّاخل‬
Damn it all!
‫أيّها الأوغاد، لن يفلتوا بفعلتهم‬
Shit! Who are they?!
‫سحقًا، من هم؟ من يعبث بسفني؟‬
Your Honor, hurry! The ship won't hold!
‫أيّها القاضي، أسرع رجاءً،‬ ‫لن تصمد هذه السّفينة‬
Whose ships are those?!
‫لمن ينتمي ذلك الأسطول؟‬
The attack on the judicial ship was a success.
‫تمّت الغارة على السّفينة القضائيّة بنجاح‬
Is that so? Then move on to the next stage of the plan.
‫فهمت... إذًا انتقلوا فورًا إلى الخطوة‬ ‫التّالية في المخطّط‬
Justice requires sacrifice.
‫هذه تضحية في سبيل العدالة‬
Yes, sir!
‫حاضر‬
So, let's start your trial now...
‫والآن، لتبدأ محاكمة... عُمّال توم...‬
The judicial ship is sinking.
‫ستغرق السّفينة القضائيّة قريبًا‬
All right. Let's pull back to Scrap Island.
‫حسنًا إذًا، لنعد إلى جزيرة المهملات‬
Okay.
‫نعم‬
Hey, the fleet is withdrawing!
‫مهلاً، الأسطول ينسحب‬
Wait a minute... I've seen those ships before!
‫مهلاً... أعرف تلك السّفن‬
Mr. Tom, the ships are returning.
‫توم-سان، السّفن عائدة إلى هنا‬
They're near the shore. We can grab 'em!
‫لقد اقتربت من السّاحل،‬ ‫أظنّنا نستطيع الإمساك بها‬
It's crazy what they did with those ships!
‫قاموا بفعل مجنون حقًّا بتلك السّفن‬
Two men from Scrap Island are coming!
‫ثمّة شخصان يركضان باتّجاهنا‬ ‫من جزيرة المهملات‬
That's Tom.
‫إنّه توم‬
Right! Abandon ship.
‫حسنًا إذًا، لنغادر السّفينة‬
What the hell?
‫ما الّذي...؟ لا أحد على متن السّفن‬
Same here. They're all deserted.
‫وهنا أيضًا، لا أحد على متن السّفن‬
Well... What's going on?
‫حسنًا... ما الّذي يجري؟‬
Those are Franky's, too.
‫تلك السّفن لفرانكي أيضًا‬
Oh no! Iceburg, watch out!
‫مصيبة، أيسبرغ احترس‬
Damn...
‫سحقًا... مقاتلات فرانكي خاصّتي‬ ‫في حالة يرثى لها‬
Iceburg! Mr. Tom!
‫أيسبرغ، توم-سان‬
Hey, you two...!
‫أنتما...‬
What's wrong?! What happened?!
‫ما الّذي يجري؟ ما الّذي حدث؟‬
Say something, Ice–
‫—أجبني، أيسـ‬
You brainless ape!
‫أيّها المعتوه‬
Those intelligence agents who visited us the other day...
‫عميل المخابرات ذاك الّذي أتى قبل أيّام...‬
They used your battleships on us!
‫استخدم سفنك الحربيّة‬
I told you.
‫ألم أخبرك؟‬
Again and again...
‫مرارًا... وتكرارًا...‬
I don't understand how you can leave dozens of these things lying around.
‫لا أعي كيف تترك العشرات منها بدمٍ بارد هنا‬
You're culpable for creating such weapons, Flunky!
‫أنا أطلب منك تحمّل مسؤوليّة‬ ‫صنعك لأسلحة قاتلة يا معتوه-كي‬
My ships... did that to Mr. Tom?!
‫توم-سان... تأذّى من قبل سفني‬
Understand...
‫اسمع‬
The weapons we create are deadly.
‫يمكن لمهاراتنا أن تجلب أسلحة‬ ‫قاتلة إلى هذا العالم...‬
Whether you intend harm or not,
‫حتّى إن كنت لا تنوي ذلك‬
weapons don't care who they hurt.
‫الأسلحة تؤذي النّاس بغضّ النّظر عن نواياك‬
Even if it's someone you love!
‫حتّى أنّها تستطيع إيذاء من هم أعزّاء على قلبك‬
The government framed us.
‫نصبت الحكومة فخًّا لنا‬
They'll accuse us of the judicial ship attack.
‫سيجعلون منّا المذنبين في مهاجمة‬ ‫السّفينة القضائيّة...‬
To get the blueprints, they need Mr. Tom as a criminal and bring him in for questioning.
‫لأنّهم يريدون استجواب توم-سان‬ ‫كمجرم للحصول على المخطّطات‬
How can you feign innocence in a situation like this?!
‫بعد كلّ هذا... أيمكنك أن تقول أنّك بريء؟‬
If we can't find a way to keep them from taking Mr. Tom away...
‫إلّم نستطع إيقافهم بطريقة ما‬ ‫من أخذ توم-سان...‬
I will...
‫لن...‬
never forgive you, Franky!
‫لن أسامحك ما حييت يا فرانكي‬
That's enough!
‫توقّفا‬
Mr. Tom!
‫توم-سان...‬
Don't blame him, Iceburg!
‫لا تلمه يا أيسبرغ‬
Franky did nothing wrong.
‫ليس خطأ فرانكي‬
How can you still say that at a time like this?!
‫أما زلت تقول هذا حتّى في هذه المرحلة؟‬
Mr. Tom!
‫توم-سان‬
I'm sorry! I made this harpoon.
‫أنا آسف، أنا من صنع هذه الحربة‬
I made it so it can't be pulled free.
‫صنعتها بحيث لا يمكن خلعها‬ ‫فور أن تخترق هدفها‬
Dammit!
‫سحقًا‬
No need to apologize! It's just a scratch.
‫لا تعتذر، هذا لا يعدّ شيئًا‬
Look, they're over there!
‫انظروا، إنّهم هناك‬
Tom's down!
‫توم ملقى على الأرض‬
How'd he get hurt so bad?!
‫لِمَ هو مصاب بشدّة هكذا؟‬
I guess they weren't in on the attack.
‫إذًا ليسوا هم من قاموا بالغارة؟‬
It's the townspeople.
‫أتى أهل البلدة‬
Well, then,
‫حسنًا إذًا...‬
I suppose we ought to start heading to town ourselves.
‫هل نذهب إلى البلدة أيضًا؟‬
Damn you, Spanda!
‫أيّها الوغد سباندا‬
That's Spandam.
‫بل "سباندام..."‬
These criminals...
‫أيّها المجرمون...‬
are responsible for the attack!
‫هؤلاء هم قادة الغارة‬
Not to worry, ladies and gentlemen.
‫اطمئنّوا جميعًا رجاءً‬
We at CP5 apprehended them after their assault.
‫نحن سي بي 5، أطحنا بهم بعد أن شنّوا الغارة‬
They're no longer a threat.
‫لا يسعهم التّسبّب في مزيدٍ من المشكلات‬
Tom's charges were about to be dropped at today's trial.
‫كان سيُبرّأ في محاكمة اليوم...‬
Why would he do something like this?
‫إذًا، لِمَ قام توم بفعل ذلك؟‬
I guess he really was in league with the Pirate King.
‫إذًا كان صديق ملك القراصنة في الأخير؟‬
Hello, nice to meet you.
‫سعيد للقائك‬
I'm Spandam of CP5.
‫أنا سباندام من السّي بي 5‬
I didn't know you were here. Thanks for your help.
‫هل صادف أن كنت هنا؟‬ ‫شكرًا لك، لقد أنقذتنا‬
We're going to need to take these men into our custody.
‫سلّمهم لنا رجاءً، لأنّنا نودّ استجوابهم‬
Try talking your way out of this. Your credibility's shot.
‫حاولوا اختلاق الأعذار إن شئتم،‬ ‫الفرق بين مصداقيّتنا شاسع‬
I, Spandam, will have the blueprints for the ancient weapon.
‫سأحصل على مخطّطات السّلاح العتيق‬
What a mess...
‫هذا فظيع...‬
First, I must say, the sea train is nothing short of spectacular.
‫أوّلاً، كلّ ما أستطيع قوله عن‬ ‫القطار البحريّ هو أنّه ممتاز‬
I'm sure it will contribute markedly to Water Seven's growing prosperity.
‫أرى أنّه سيساهم إلى حدّ كبير‬ ‫في ازدهار ووتر سيفن‬
For the previous charge of building Gold Roger's ship
‫وبسبب ذلك، بخصوص تهمتك‬ ‫السّابقة ببناء سفينة غولد روجر‬
that alone was enough to justify your upcoming acquittal today.
‫قرّرنا وبصفة نهائيّة اليوم أن نقوم بتبرئتك‬
So why commit another crime?
‫إذًا، لماذا ارتكبت جريمة أخرى؟‬
What a joke!
‫هذا هراء‬
We didn't attack the judicial ship!
‫لسنا من أغاروا على السّفينة القضائيّة‬
That bastard Spandam over there did it!
‫بل ذلك المدعوّ سباندام‬
Are you kidding?
‫مستحيل‬
What is Tom's apprentice going on about?
‫ما بال تلميذ توم يلقي بنكته فجأةً؟‬
What would the government agency CP5 have to gain from sinking the judicial ship?
‫ما الفائدة الّتي قد تجنيها السّي بي 5‬ ‫كيان حكوميّ، من إغراق السّفينة القضائيّة؟‬
Ridiculous. That's just impossible.
‫يا له من قول غبيّ! هذا ليس ممكنًا إطلاقًا!‬
Cutty Flam, was it?
‫اسمك كاتي فلام، صحيح؟‬
Let's not forget that we caught you red-handed on one of the raid ships.
‫أساسًا، قبضنا عليك متلبّسًا‬ ‫على إحدى سفن الغارة‬
Moreover, your company built all those ships, right?
‫فضلاً عن ذلك، ألم تكن سفن الغارة‬ ‫تلك من بناء شركتكم؟‬
Ships that could cause such havoc...
‫سفن قد تفعل شيئًا كذاك...‬
Those... are no longer...
‫ما... عادت...‬
my ships!
‫سفني‬
Tom broke his cuffs!
‫لقد كسر توم أصفاده‬
Ready arms!
‫استعدّوا‬
That's the first time... Mr. Tom has ever hit Franky...
‫توم-سان... ضرب فرانكي للمرّة الأولى...‬
What the hell?!
‫لم فعلت ذلك؟‬
"Those are no longer my ships"?!
‫أقلت "ما عادت سفني"؟‬
That's the one thing you can never say!
‫قل أيّ شيء إلّا ذلك‬
What's wrong with that?! I regret everything!
‫وما الضّير في قول ذلك؟‬ ‫لقد ندمتُ على بنائها‬
If I never made those ships, no one would've gotten hurt!
‫لو أنّني لم أبنها، لما تأذّى أيّ أحد‬
No matter what kind of ship it is, the act of building it...
‫أيًّا كان نوع السّفينة، فعملُ بنائها...‬
is neither an act of good nor evil!
‫لا يعدّ عملاً صالحًا ولا طالحًا‬
I don't care what kind of ships you build.
‫لا يهمّني أيّ نوعٍ من السّفن قرّرت أن تبني‬
However,
‫لكن حتّى إن قامت بإيذاء أحدهم‬ ‫بل وحتّى إن دمّرت العالم‬
you, as their creator, must love them.
‫على من بناها أن يحبّها على الأقلّ‬
You must not deny what you have created.
‫لا يجب على من بناها أن يتبرّأ منها‬
Never blame the ship!
‫لا تلم السّفن‬
A man should be damn proud of the ships he builds!
‫على المرء أن يفتخر بعزم... بالسّفن الّتي بناها‬
Iceburg... Franky...
‫أيسبرغ...‬
don't interfere with what I'm about to do...
‫لا تتدخّلا فيمَ سأفعله الآن...‬
no matter what!
‫مهما كان‬
First, the World Government frames me. And now it passes judgment on me.
‫حكومة العالم هي من لفّقت لنا الجريمة‬
There's no way to wipe the slate clean now...
‫يستحيل أن نتبرّأ من الشّكوك‬
This is how it ends.
‫هذه هي النهاية‬
It must be tough to see your innocent ships used for such depravity.
‫لا بدّ أنّ من الصّعب عليك‬ ‫أن ترى سفنك البريئة تُستخدم هكذا‬
I bet you want to hit him, Franky.
‫لا بدّ أنّك تريد أن توسع ذلك‬ ‫الشّخص ضربًا، أليس كذلك يا فرانكي؟‬
Mr. Tom!
‫توم-سان‬
Tom's going on a rampage!
‫أخذ توم يهيج‬
What's he doing?!
‫يا إلهي...‬
Stop it! If you keep this up...
‫توقّف رجاءً، إن لمسته مرّة أخرى...‬
have any idea how much you've hurt that boy?!
‫الألم الّذي يشعر به؟‬
F-Fire!
‫أ-أطلقوا النّار‬
They shot him...
‫لقد أطلقوا عليه...‬
Mr. Tom!
‫توم-سان‬
Tranquilizer darts, huh?
‫رصاصات مهدّئة إذًا؟‬
Suck on that, you monstrous fishman!
‫أيّها البرمائيّ اللّعين ذو القوّة الخارقة!‬ ‫نلت ما تستحقّ!‬
Mr. Tom, why'd you do that?!
‫توم-سان، لم فعلت ذلك؟‬
Hey, what are you morons doing?! Take them into custody already!
‫أنتم، ماذا تفعلون؟ أسرعوا واقبضوا عليهم‬
I had no idea Tom was such a violent guy.
‫لا أصدّق أنّ توم شخص خطير...‬
What is he thinking?!
‫فيمَ يفكّر بالضّبط؟‬
They built those battleships just for this purpose!
‫صنع العديد من السّفن الحربيّة‬ ‫وانتظر فرصته هكذا‬
How can you say such a thing about Mr. Tom?!
‫أيّها الأوغاد، كيف تجرؤون على‬ ‫الحديث هكذا مع توم-سان؟‬
Let it be!
‫توقّف‬
It's fine.
‫لا بأس‬
But...!
‫لكن...‬
Your Honor.
‫أيّها القاضي...‬
I plead guilty to the judicial ship attack.
‫سأعترف بتهمة إغارة السّفينة القضائيّة‬
What?!
‫ماذا؟‬
Wait! Mr. Tom, take it back!
‫مهلاً يا توم-سان، لا تفعل‬
However, I have just one request.
‫لكنّي أملك معروفًا أطلبه‬
Screw you, you stupid fishman! Who would grant a criminal a favor?!
‫اخرس أيّها البرمائيّ الغبيّ‬
Silence, CP5!
‫أطبق فمك يا سي بي 5‬
What is your request?
‫ما المعروف إذًا؟‬
If I can get one crime absolved for our building of the sea train...
‫إن كنتُ أستطيع إسقاط تهمة واحدة‬ ‫كتعويض لبنائنا القطار البحريّ...‬
I request that it be today's offense.
‫أودّ أن تُسقط تهمة اليوم‬
If I were to grant your request, you'll go right back to square one.
‫حتّى إن لبّينا لك ذلك الطّلب‬ ‫ستعود إلى الصّفر‬
You'd still be guilty of building the Pirate King's ship, a capital offense.
‫ستُتّهم في النّهاية بجريمة بناء‬ ‫سفينة من أجل...‬
That's right. I'd prefer that.
‫نعم، أفضّل ذلك‬
Yeah, I helped the man called Roger.
‫أمّا بشأن مساعدة المدعوّ روجر...‬
I'm damn proud of it too!
‫أنا فخور بذلك بعزم‬
Of all the self-serving...
‫يا لأنانيّته...‬
Imagine being proud of helping the King of the Pirates...
‫بأن يكون فخورًا بمساعدة ملك القراصنة...‬
He's a traitor!
‫خائن‬
– Fishman thug! – Damn fishman!
‫برمائيّ متوحّش‬
Mr. Tom... Why?!
‫توم-سان... لماذا؟‬
I'm fine with this.
‫لا بأس‬
Listen to me. Don't beat yourself up.
‫اسمع، لا تلم نفسك، اتّفقنا؟‬
I had no idea the government was this determined to get the blueprints.
‫لم أتخيّل أنّ الحكومة ستلجأ‬ ‫إلى العنف لأخذ المخطّطات‬
My work with Roger put me at a bit of a disadvantage.
‫كنتُ في موقفٍ ضعف بسبب مسألتي مع روجر‬
But even so, you didn't have to–
‫—لكن مع ذلك، لم تكن بحاجةٍ لـ‬
It's fine.
‫لا تقلق‬
Look, even if the charges go back fourteen years, everything has changed since then.
‫انظر إلى البلدة، حتّى إن عادت تهمتي‬ ‫لما كانت عليه قبل 14 سنة‬
The island has really come to life.
‫باتت هذه الجزيرة مليئة بالطّاقة الآن‬
This is just the beginning.
‫وما هذه إلّا البداية‬
No matter what happens to me,
‫مهما حصل لي‬
I'll still be of service to the city.
‫استطعتُ مساعدة البلدة‬
My dream...
‫حلمي...‬
has only just left the station.
‫قد بدأ... يسير أخيرًا‬
Mr. Tom!
‫توم-سان‬
Iceberg... Franky...
‫أيسبرغ... فرانكي...‬
take care of those blueprints.
‫اعتنيا بالمخطّطات‬
Miss Kokoro... Yokozuna...
‫كوكورو-سان... يوكوزونا...‬
thank you for everything.
‫شكرًا لكما على كلّ شيء‬
The tranquilizers kicked in!
‫بدأ مفعول المهدّئات أخيرًا‬
Arrest those three for attacking the judicial ship!
‫أمسكوا أولئك الجناة الثّلاثة بتهمة‬ ‫إغارة السّفينة القضائيّة‬
– Yes, sir!
‫حاضر‬
Belay that order.
‫انتظروا‬
The charges have changed.
‫سأغيّر التّهم‬
For the crime of building Pirate King Gold Roger's pirate ship,
‫بتهمة بناء سفينة قراصنة لملك القراصنة، غولد روجر‬
we shall escort the shipwright Tom to Enies Lobby.
‫سنأخذ السفان توم إلى إنيس لوبي‬
That is all.
‫رُفعت الجلسة‬
What's gotten into that sentimental old coot?
‫ما بال ذلك العجوز الخرف؟‬
Whatever. I have no need for his apprentices.
‫لا يهمّ، لا شأن لي بتلميذيه‬
Free the two apprentices!
‫أطلقا سراح تلميذيه‬
Mr. Tom is beyond saving now.
‫ما عدنا نستطيع إنقاذ توم-سان‬
There's nothing we can do against the World Government.
‫إن كنّا نواجه حكومة العالم‬ ‫فليس هناك ما نستطيع فعله‬
Stay strong, you two. Mr. Tom saved your lives!
‫تحمّلا، توم-سان أنقذكما‬
If you make an enemy of them, you'll be dead before the day is out.
‫إن اتّخذتماهم أعداءً لكما‬
Enies Lobby, the Judicial Island, belongs to the government.
‫إنيس لوبي هي الجزيرة القضائيّة‬ ‫الّتي تمتلكها الحكومة‬
None of the criminals sent there have ever come back!
‫لم يسبق أن أخذوا مجرمًا...‬
The sea train is ready for departure!
‫القطار البحريّ جاهز، يمكننا أخذه الآن‬
All right!
‫جيّد‬
Miss Kokoro...
‫كوكورو-سان...‬
Hey, you guys, get him out of here now!
‫أنتم، أسرعوا وخذوا...‬
I...
‫أنا...‬
This... heavy... insane fishman!
‫هذا البرمائيّ الثّقيل المجنون‬
Hey!
‫أنت‬
Franky, no!
‫توقّف‬
He caved in Agent Spandam's face!
‫لقد حطّم وجه سباندام-سان‬
This time it's Tom's apprentice who's rampaging!
‫هذه المرّة، بدأ تلميذ توم يهيج‬
That's enough!
‫توقّف‬
Seize him! Everyone else, get Tom out of here!
‫اقبضوا عليه، وليقم بقيّتكم بأخذ توم‬
Just try it! I won't let you take him!
‫فليكن، لن أدعكم تأخذوه‬
Fire at will!
‫بإمكانكم إطلاق النّار عليه‬
Let Mr. Tom go!
‫أعيدوا لنا توم-سان‬
Are you okay?!
‫هل أنت بخير؟‬
Run for it!
‫أسرع واهرب‬
Fire!
‫أطلقوا‬
Dammit! He got away!
‫سحقًا، لقد هرب‬
I'll never forgive that punk, Cutty Flam!
‫لن أدع ذلك الشّقيّ كاتي فلام يفلت بهذا أبدًا‬
He's a damned criminal!
‫إنّه مجرم بحقّ‬
When this is over, I'll send that moron to the gallows!
‫بمجرّد انتهاء هذه القضيّة، سأرسله إلى المشنقة‬
Agent Spandam!
‫سباندام-سان‬
What?!
‫ماذا تريد؟‬
I-It's Cutty Flam!
‫إ-إنّه كاتي فلام‬
What do you mean?!
‫ماذا؟‬
He intercepted us!
‫لقد لاحقنا حتّى هنا‬
He's on the tracks ahead with some kind of weapon.
‫وهو واقف على السّكّة بسلاح ما‬
Wait right there, Yokozuna.
‫ابقَ هناك يا يوكوزونا‬
Is he an imbecile?!
‫أهو غبيّ أم ماذا؟‬
What's your order?
‫ما العمل؟‬
Are you an imbecile?!
‫هل أنت غبيّ أيضًا؟‬
Just keep going! We'll give him what he wants.
‫تابع فحسب وأعطه ما يريد،‬ ‫لا تلقِ بالاً له‬
Y-Yes, sir.
‫حـ-حاضر‬
Stop, Puffing Tom!
‫توقّف يا توم النّافث‬
Where do you think you're taking the man who created you?!
‫إلى أين تأخذ صانعك؟‬
This is the end of the line!
‫لن أدعك تمرّ‬
Give me back Mr. Tom!
‫أعيدوا توم-سان لنا‬
Stop, sea train!
‫توقّف، أيّها القطار البحريّ‬
So your parents abandoned you? Hilarious!
‫فهمت، تخلّا عنك والداك إذًا؟‬
Hey, don't laugh so hard!
‫أنت، إنّك تضحك بشدّة‬
Well, you're damn welcome at my house.
‫حسنًا إذًا، تعال إلى بيتي بعزم‬
Mr. Tom...
‫توم-سان...‬
to be honest, I... don't want to build ships anymore.
‫ما عدت أريد بناء السّفن‬
I can't love a ship that has hurt someone precious to me!
‫لا يمكنني أن أحبّ السّفن‬ ‫الّتي تؤذي من أهتمّ لهم كثيرًا‬
But, Mr. Tom...
‫لكن يا توم-سان...‬
I still want to be like you!
‫أنت قدوتي في النّهاية‬
I want you to come home and keep teaching me!
‫لذا أريدك أن تعود وتعلّمني ثانيةً...‬
I, too,
‫لأنّني أريد أن...‬
want to build my dream ship!
‫أبني سفينة الأحلام يومًا أيضًا‬
A ship... that damn well traverses even uncharted waves the world over!
‫سفينة تعبر بعزم وفخر حتّى الأمواج‬ ‫المجهولة في أقاصي الأرض‬
That's my dream ship!
‫سفينة أحلام كتلك‬